Target scope, open.
Target, fixed.
All hands, prepare for shock and flash.
Electro-reflex sight brightness 20.
Ten seconds until firing.
Nine.
Eight.
Seven.
Six.
Five.
Four.
Three.
Domon !
I should have done this sooner.
Yamato, what are you doing ?!
All hands, prepare for
hand-to-hand combat !
Don't let the enemy enter the ship...
Talan...
...prepare to self-destruct...
...although it probably won't be
enough to sink this fortress.
A...aye, sir !
Kodai, are you going to let me die for nothing ?
Help, I need your help !
I beg you !
There's a way to save everyone !
Mr. Yabu, I need your help !
But I can't leave my post now.
Ryusuke, don't tell me you...
I have permission.
I don't know what he's thinking either !
Miyako, Sakamoto !
You too ?
What's going on ?
I was about to take off.
Must be that Ryusuke again...
Get in now.
We're taking off immediately.
Captain Kodai ?!
So, tell me, why do I have to accompany you in exchange for accepting my plan ?
I pointed a gun at you.
"I should have done this sooner."
You're right...
...but that won't necessarily lead to success.
Reality is complex and cruel.
You'll be hurt less if you accept
such unreasonable situations.
That's one of the correct viewpoints.
But, even so, we have
things we can't give up.
If you're told to give up, you must resist.
Don't worry about your position.
Fight every inch of the
way so you can be yourself.
I'd forgotten about it...
...for far too long.
Captain Kodai...
Let's make up for lost time.
Don't bite your tongue.
I see.
That's what Captain Kodai decided.
I understand.
I'll get to it right away.
Thank you, Captain Mori, Captain Sanada.
All ships, come about 180 degrees !
To all joint fleet ships...
...the Earth fleet will commence an
operation to rescue Führer Desler.
Follow us if you so desire.
We need your help
to divert enemy attention.
Migrant fleet, continue moving
and get as far away as possible.
If you're willing to join, show your
intent by turning your ships around.
They are the ones who broke the promise.
You can't complain now, Queen Starsha.
They're fighting again ?
Abelt...
Encrypted transmission ?
From the Earth fleet...
Just one pattern...
Open the flight deck.
Prototype dimensional submarine,
ready for take off.
"Cosmo Hound" ?
The development team named it.
This is the Earth force's
first dimensional submarine.
It's a stupid dog, one prone to
failing once every three times.
Seriously ?
Sounds good.
It's a perfect companion for you.
Cosmo Hound, take off !
Emergency dive.
Dimensional submersion echo detected.
Unknown wave length.
What's the situation outside the ship ?
The joint fleet is still fighting.
Yamato is repeatedly telling us to escape.
What are you thinking ?
Kodai...
I don’t know how you do things
on Iscandar, but on Earth…
...a person who falls in love with an
Earthling's sibling becomes family.
You loved my brother,
which makes you my sister.
Nothing else matters.
I want you to come to Earth with me.
I...
...don't want to lose my family again !
Sister !
If you don't leave,
Führer Desler won't withdraw.
It might sound foolish.
We humans are foolish.
We act irrationally for the
sake of important things.
Starsha, if you are human,
I want you to be foolish !
Throw everything away !
Then muster the courage to leave this graveyard !
Let's go, Sister.
We aren't ghosts who subject ourselves
to reliving the past in perpetuity.
We are also "life."
We should live unpredictable
lives, moving toward the future.
Yurisha...
Whether it’s for a minute, or even
a second, it's of no consequence.
If I can live just one genuine, fulfilled life…
...then I want to live it !
It's the same wave length from earlier.
Dimensional submersion echo detected
directly below the Iscandar palace.
So that's your aim, is it ?
Release the net !
No abnormalities.
How do you feel ?
I'm happy with your decision.
But we can't let them
have Iscandar like this.
What is it ?
Sonar contact. It's getting bigger.
That thing swallowed the
Garmillas submarine earlier…
It's coming ! It's coming !
It's closing in !
Everyone, this is the moment of truth.
Breathe together as if rowing a cutter boat.
We're all in this together !
Domon.
It's your plan.
You command this operation.
Aye, sir !
Thrust is unstable !
I see it !
Dimensional boundary in sight !
The enemy is faster than expected !
We're still good.
Count down as planned.
T-minus ten.
Eight.
Seven.
Six.
Five.
Four.
Three.
Two.
One !
Heave-ho !
What's wrong ?!
No good ! The lock's stuck !
It's malfunctioning !
I've gotta check the circuit !
There's no time for that !
This stupid dog !
Crap, we'll be captured !
Sakamoto, down trim.
Reverse speed 2.
Raiden, don't give up !
Only one lock is stuck.
Keep pushing.
But...
Is "brave" only in your surname, Caroline ?
Tasuke, channel more power !
That's impossible !
We won't be able to surface !
Once the ship gets lighter,
we'll be able to ! Do it !
Don't mess with me !
Target captured.
We only need the royals to
manage their accursed power.
That's...
Domon...
Wave motion energy response
detected inside the enemy ship.
It's a trap !
Get it out of the Golva now !
Exp
Wave Motion Excavator
Your Excellency...
Führer Desler, we've rescued Queen Starsha.
I suggest that you escape now.
Abelt...
Talan...
Sir.
The records have become distorted.
The thousand-year dream of
Dezariam has become warped.
By just one bomb ? How ?!
Wave motion energy…that accursed power.
Mœlders !
Follow Dezariam doctrine...
...and sink that accursed ship !
High energy response
detected in the enemy fortress !
Fan out !
Tell the advanced migrant ships to do the same !
Response getting stronger !
We won't make it in time !
Abelt...
Starsha...
Those eyes…
they've always been fixed on me.
I'll never forget it.
Thank you...
We're memories of Iscandar.
Since the planet is gone,
we're destined to disappear.
But this child is different…
...due to an element unique
to your kind's planet.
Namely, the love shared between Kodai Mamoru
and my sister, which gave birth to a life such as this.
Sasha, make sure to have fun on Earth, okay ?
You knew ?!
Why would you…
If you knew this'd happen, why ?!
It saved a soul.
Even for a brief moment, he was able to
meet the person he loved for the last time.
That alone can save a person.
For the last time...
My father looked at me...
That's the best one human
can do for another human.
That should be enough.
That must be enough.
It has to be.
Everyone can go onboard.
Don't rush, stay calm and move
to the ships you've been assigned to.
So this is Starsha's...
Should I send it to quarantine ?
A baby ?!
Sasha...
Sasha ?
Starsha and my brother's...
Welcome home.
Hello, Sasha.
Daddy ?
Did you know ?
When you feel the worst, something
wonderful is right around the corner.
This blue blood and skin...
The people of Garmillas will
eventually discover our origins.
However, we'll remain
proud of the name Garmillas.
Pride cannot be given.
You develop it in
your heart yourself.
Führer Desler...
I appreciate you letting me see Starsha.
Even if it was just for a moment, I received
enough to live for the rest of my life.
Take care of her child.
Kodai, make sure to never let go...
...of that which you love.
In the crumbling world...
koware yuku sekai
...even fire and hope freeze
hi mo kibou mo kooru
But only tears are warm
demo namida dakewa atatakai
Behind the sorrow...
kanashimi no ushiro de itsumo
...happiness always waits for you
tsugi wa shiawase ga matteiru
Let's turn that fairy tale into truth
sonna guuwa wo shinjitsuni kaemashou
You whisper with a spark in your eye
anata no me ga mabushisouni sasayaku
You don't dream to get hurt
yume wo miru no wa kizutsuku tame janai
In the crumbling world...
koware yuku sekai
...even fire and hope freeze
hi mo kibou mo kooru
But only tears are warm
demo namida dakewa atatakai
Hello, Sasha
Final Episode
Those were inside the enemy fortress ?
We managed to photograph them when
the wave motion excavator went in.
Andromeda-class ?
They could have been captured...
I thought that at first, but...
The numbers indicate that there are far
more vessels out there than we ever built.
Dezariam...
Who are they really ?
Be Forever Yamato